JANE CASTO

(415) 497-6608 / contact@janecasto.com / Davis, CA 95616

PORTFOLIO

To see some of my projects, visit janecasto.com

PROFILE

After studying at The University of California, Davis for 4 years, I will be graduating with my Bachelor's in Political Science in June 2023. Through my studies and work in activism, I have developed a deep appreciation for community-driven policy, which I believe can be developed or strengthened with accurate data and policy analysis. I hope to become a full-time public policy analyst, using what I have learned of policy and statistical analysis, visualization, and management to provide important support for communities in California.

SKILLS

Proficient In:

Community Activism - 6 years, Policy Analysis - 4 years, Microsoft Suite - 6 years, Excel and Google Sheets - 4 years, Statistics and Analytics - 4 years, SQL - 1 year, R - 2 years, Tableau - 2 years, Python - 2 years, Jira - 2 years,

General Skills:

Communication, Attention to Detail, Time-Management, Teamwork, Adaptability.

EXPERIENCE

Instructor - Play-Well TEKnologies

June 2022 - March 2023

Taught kids engineering through legos and held community events to help parents understand benefits of such programs, especially for under-represented kids. Specialized in ensuring gender inclusion in classrooms predominantly seen as spaces for boys.

Research Assistant – Feminist Research Institute

March 2020 - May 2021

Assisted researchers in studies aimed at understanding educational inequity and discouragement. Ran focus groups and ethically utilized anonymized data to create visualizations, spotlight data, and more aimed at fueling campus policy change. Utilized Excel/Sheets and Jira for project management and Tableau for visualizations.

Chairperson – Associate Students of University of California, Davis *June* 2020 - September 2021

Chaired the Gender and Sexuality Commission of ASUCD. Crafted legislation on campus, including increased programs, protections and options for survivors of sexual assault, inclusion of feminine hygiene products in campus bathrooms, and more.

Organizer – Marin Organizing for Racial Equity (M.O.R.E)

January 2017 - June 2019

Planned and executed events for addressing racial equity issues in Marin County. This included gathering data on racial equity for presentations to the Civic Center, speaking at community events about our findings, and more.

EDUCATION

University of California, Davis - 2019 - 2023

Fields of study: Political Science & Gender/Women's Studies.

Google Data Analytics Certification - 2023

Certification is current. Contents include: Tableau, SQL, R, Spreadsheets, and Ethics. Verify this certificate at **this link**, **via Coursera**.